I have a 26 years old son.
He played sports
and was scouted for university.
But due to an incident
with a senior student,
he ended up dropping out of the school.
He quit playing sports
and tried to re-enter university
with an academic major, but couldn't.
So he gave up on school,
worked part-time jobs in Seoul.
And yet that didn't work out well either.
One day he came home, I said to him:
"Why not go down to Geoje
and work in the shipbuilding industry
rather than wasting time?
He must've given some thought into this.
He eventually applied and got a job.
So he worked there for a while.
Now his salary wasn't much.
He must have thought
that it paid too little,
hence a waste of life.
One day he quit to find another job
with better pay.
And yet once he quit,
things weren't as easy as he thought.
So he'd end up hanging out
in Internet cafes.
He'd stay at Internet cafes all night, he'd come
home during the day to sleep. I live with him
and yet it's been months since I've seen him.
He eventually spent all his savings
and started using his credit card.
He asked me to pay off $200
of his credit card debt,
saying he'd get a job and pay it back.
Given it was a small amount
and his first time asking for help,
I paid his bill saying it's for one time only.
He agreed it was a one time thing.
And yet it wasn't the last time.
He'd get a job but would quit
after a few days.
I'm now sleep deprived
and suffering with anger issues.
And yet he demands
that I pay off his credit card debt.
I'm not sure
if I should keep paying off his debt
or just let him become delinquent.
I'm unsure what to do as a parent.
I'm suffering so much
that I feel like fainting.
I feel as if I'm developing
a mental disorder.
I'm very concerned.
Hearing what you've said,
I don't see a big problem.
The person who's struggling is you,
not your son.
The fact of the matter is,
I'm a parent and my son's a good kid. What can I do?
He has another bill to pay off.
If you pay off his bill this time,
he'll be asking for more.
You'll pay off $200 this time.
Next time it'll be $500,
and then $1000, $2000.
Then should I leave him
to become delinquent?
If you don't pay off his debt...
He said he'll leave the house
or kill himself.
He said he'll leave.
Yes, he may kill himself. It's possible.
Yes, he said so himself.
He said he doesn't want to live anymore.
Hence he asked for one last chance.
Okay.
Then you now need to make a decision.
If you think he's better off dying,
make the call.
Don't assume this will be the last time
you'll be paying off his debt.
If you pay him now,
you'll be paying him off again and again.
Assume that it'll be an ongoing thing.
And make a call
between the two options.
If I don't pay it off for him,
he'll end up financially delinquent
and in a deep trouble, won't he?
Not only that but he may kill himself.
Ah...
A son is threatening his mother
right now.
If he says he'll kill himself,
can a mother ignore?
I can't if he says he'll kill himself.
That's right. No reason to even ask then.
He's already implying
and threatening to kill himself.
Now if you give into the threat,
you'll have to give in every time
going forward.
I'll probably continue paying off his debt, won't I?
Yes, you'll have to accept that.
If you think it's better off having him live than die,
don't take it as a threat and just pay it off.
But do keep in mind
that this won't be your last time.
You mean it won't be the last time
I pay off his debt?
No, it won't be your last time.
It was $200 at first. This time it's $500.
Next time it'll be $1000, $5000.
It'll get bigger and bigger.
Are you willing to take that?
Or would you rather resolve the situation by saying,
"You're over 20 years old,
you should take charge of your own life."
Would you rather stop this vicious
cycle by accepting the possibility
that he may die?
It's hard to imagine him dying,
but it's just as hard to see him live
like this.
You have to make up your mind
between the two.
There is no other way.
The best outcome as a parent would
be for your son to become independent
and not kill himself, right?
If I trust him once more...
It's not about trusting him once more.
It will happen again irrespectively.
Again and again?
Yes.
Really?
Then what should I do?
I'm not even capable of paying off
his debt every time.
Well, you can't pay it off
if you don't have the money.
You can't afford to help him
if you're not capable of doing so.
So will you let him drag you around
given the risk that he might kill himself?
If not, you'll have to accept
the possibility of him dying
in order to fix his bad ways.
So I have to be willing to see him die
if I want him to change?
If you can tell yourself,
"He's better off dying than living like this"
and accept his death serenely, it's fine.
But if he really does die
and you cry saying,
"I should have just paid off
whatever he asked for",
then you'd be regretting.
Then you'll suffer even after his death.
You'd be suffering while he's alive,
you'd suffer while he's dead.
There won't be an end.
Yes, I feel like that will happen.
So don't drag it out. Make a decision.
Okay. I'll think about it again
and make up my mind.
Why think about it again?
Make up your mind right now
and act upon it.
It's not like you'll have a better idea
once you go home, no?
You have two choices.
I'm suffering so much because of that.
Then just pay off his debt for him.
It seems like you're willing to pay it off.
Just know that once you pay it off
this time,
you'll be paying it off again and again,
10 times more the amount.
You can say it's your last time,
but think to yourself,
"I can't not pay him off going forward.
Such is life."
Then you'll at least sleep well.
You would've made up your mind,
so you'll struggle less.
I'll do that since he's my son. Thank you.
If I were you, I'd do this.
If a little kid makes a fuss over food,
I'd take away his plate
and let him starve for three days.
If a teenager says
he'll run away from home,
I'd kick him out,
lock the door and not let him back in.
I'd only let him in when he begs
for forgiveness.
I can say this
because I'm a childless monk.
But you as a parent,
you follow your kids around
with food begging,
"Please eat. I'm sorry, please eat."
If your kids run away,
you look all over for them.
If they threaten to kill themselves,
you give them everything.
You can't help it.
There are other solutions,
but most of you can't follow through.
Hence you'll let your kids drag you
around all your life.
If you can detach, you can say
"You're an adult,
you take care of your own self.
I have nothing to do
with your decisions."
And then you shouldn't regret.
Look at the hens.
If you try and grab their young chicks,
the hens will attack you.
But once the chicks grow older,
the mother hens don't care
whether you catch them or eat them.
They live their lives freely.
And yet humans spend all their lives
worrying over their children even
when they're 68.
The questioner is going to end up
just like her in 20 years' time.
There won't be a difference.